A Guide to the Dandridge Spotswood Papers, 1585-1939
Library of Virginia
- Papers, 1619-1935, .225 cubic feet
  - Papers, 1585-1939 (Folder 17)
    - Order, 21 February 1699/1700, in regard to a pirate, Governor's Council., 156; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 16 July 1705, William Richardson to Messrs. Perry and Cowper[?]., 157; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 26 [January?] 1748, unknown correspondent in Louisbourg, [Cape Breton, Canada], to unknown recipient., 158; 4 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letters, 1750, from [Thomas, Lord?] Fairfax to Guy Broadwater of Frederick County, Virginia, concerning surveying., 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 July 1758, unknown correspondent to "George.", 160; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 25 December 1762, Thomas Jefferson to [John] Page., 161; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - advertisement, 7 December 1767, in Charlotte County, Virginia, for care of poor persons in Cornwall Parish., 1 leaf, typewritten and copy.
    - Letter, 23 January 1776[?], Benjamin Moore of Dunmore [Shenandoah] County, [Virginia], to Colonel Peter Moore[?] of Martinsburg, [(West) Virginia]. Also includes letter, 29 May 1775, from Isaac Zane to Captain Jacob Haleman[?] of Dunmore County., 163; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Message, 9 July 1775, from David Duncan to the Shawanee. Message signed by John Connally. Also includes letter, 16 December 1811, from James Monroe in Washington D.C., to Joseph Monroe of Charlottesville, Virginia., 164; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Oath of allegiance, 23 April 1779, of Joel Watkins of Charlotte County. Includes biographical note of Watkins and an obituary, January 1820, of Watkins written by John Randolph of Roanoke., 165; 2 leaves, typewritten and copy.
    - Letter, 8 June 1781, [General George] Weedon[?] to unknown recipient. Miscellaneous notes on back., 166; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 16 May 1782, John Tyler, in Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson., 167; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 16 December 1787, John Dandridge of New Kent County, [Virginia], to John Hopkins of Richmond., 168; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 20 April 1807, A. Spotswood of Spotsylvania County to Edmund Randolph., 169; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letters, 25 January 1815, Petersburg Volunteers to Anna Matilda Hening of Richmond. Includes a copy of Anna Matilda Hening's reply., 170; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 13 June 1834, Elizabeth Hamilton of New York, New York, to Mrs. Grant of England. Elizabeth Hamilton was the wife of Alexander Hamilton. Also includes biographical notes on the writer and recipient of the letter., 171; 2 leaves, typewritten with copy of letter.
    - Letter, 13 April 1844, E. Blair[?] Lee to R. J. Walker. Also includes letter, 30 March 1845, from N. P. Talmadge to unknown recipient., 172; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - article, September 1858, from a Petersburg newspaper reprinting the reception of General Nathanael Greene by the city of Petersburg in October 1784., 173; 1 leaf, typewritten with copy.
    - Remarks, 5 January 1873, by an unknown individual., 174; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Notice, 23 August 1878, concerning the death of William Niblo of New York., 175; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Miscellaneous items, 1830-1937, on Joice Heth, Washington's dry nurse; burning of the home of Donald Mackenzie in Petersburg in 1920; announcement of the death of John Dunlop of London in 1830 and copied in 1937; and genealogical note tracing the ancestry of Robert E. Lee back to Duncan and Robert the Bruce, kings of Scotland., 176; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - article, 7 May 1939, from the Richmond Times-Dispatch, concering Major Heros von Borcke., 177; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Notes, n.d., on Dolly Madison, including correspondence., 178; 14 p., typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., General Stonewall Jackson to General Lafayette McLaws., 179; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Note, n.d., on the Crockett family and description of coat-of-arms., 180; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Reminiscences, n.d., of Mrs. William Henry Wager of Shreveport, Louisiana., 181; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Moses Hoge to Thomas Jones of Campbell County, [Virginia]. Includes notes on Jones' son James., 182; 1 leaf, typritten with copy.
    - Letters, various dates, regarding medicine and medical treatments. Includes letter from Mildred Roberdeau, Elisha Cullen Dick, and Bushrod Washington., 183; 2 leaves, typewritten with copy.
    - Letter, n.d., George T. Swann, Brandon Mississippi, to Sarah W. Swann of Cumberland County, [Virginia]., 184; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., from the citizens of Salisbury, North Carolina, to [George Washington]., 185; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, n.d., Henry Patillo to unknown recipient. Includes letter, n.d., to Mr. R. Harrison., 186; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Note, n.d., birth and baptism information for Priscilla, daughter of James and Mary Banks., 187; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Note, n.d., on the death of John Randolph of Roanoke., 188; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, n.d., Mary Campbell of Virginia to an unknown recipient., 189; 2 leaves, typewritten with two copies.
    - Letter, n.d., S. C. Bott of Petersburg to "Frances.", 190; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, 1653-1879 (Folder 18)
    - Challenge, ca. 1652, to a duel from Thomas Hackett to his son-in-law Richard Denham[?]., 191; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 6 December 1653, Willy[?] Scopes to thomas Willoughby, Lemuel Mason, and John Holmes of Virginia., 192; 3 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letters, 1717, of Francis Pollock of North Carolina to Governor Charles Eden of North Carolina and Thomas Pollock of North Carolina to Sir Robert Pollock., 193; 7 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 25 August 1725, William Pepperells [Pepperell] of Massachusetts to Roger Prowse. Includes reply, 8 February 1726, from Prowse., 194; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 21 January 1735, William Byrd of Charles City County, [Virginia], to Sir John Randolph., 195; 3 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 6 June 1755, George Croghan of Fort Luther, Pennsylvania, to [George Washington]., 196; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 5 September 1755, Joseph Ball of Stratford, England, to George Washington. Also includes notes on St. Paul's Parish [possibly of Stafford County, Virginia] and its minister William Stuart., 197; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Advertisement, 11 November 1756, for Joseph Borden's stage boat., 198; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1 December 1756, John Andrew Henderson of Augusta County, Virginia, to "John.", 199; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 31 May 1769, Philip Lee of Stratford Hall, Westmoreland County, [Virginia], to his brother [possibly Francis Lightfoot Lee]., 200; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 9 June 1770, B. Arnold to B. Douglas of New Haven, Connecticut., 201; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 28 September 1771, Bernard Moore of Virginia to John Norton of London., 202; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 12 October 1771, Richard Randolph of "Blanford" to Captain Thomas Munford of the Brig Norborne., 203; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 23 September 1775, from an unknown correspondent of Fredericksburg, [Virginia], to Messrs. Dixon and Hunter, published in the Williamsburg Gazette., 204; 1 leaf, typewritten with a copy.
    - Letter, 12 July 1780, Ezra Stiles to Bishop James Madison., 4 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 7 August 1780, G. Clinton to [Charles or Thomas] Lee., 206; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - letter, 2 December 1780, Francis Lightfoot Lee, in Richmond, to Becky Tayloe [Lee?]., 207; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 1782, [Achibald Cary?] to John Sarmavage[?] of Buckingham County, [Virginia]. Includes letter, 6 March 1782, from Archibald Cary to Colonel Davis., 208; 4 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, 1783, George Washington to the Marquis de Lafayette., 209; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 9 October 1784, Samuel [?] to Jonathan Smith of Philadelphia., 210; 4p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 22 June 1785, Charles Mynn Thurston to Captain Thomas Baytop. Also includes letter, 2 March 1809, from Jasper S. Clayton to Thomas Baytop., 211; 1 leaf, typewritten. Includes a second typewritten copy and a handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 12 February 1801, Aaron Burr, Albany, New York, to Thomas Jefferson., 212; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 18 July 1806, unknown correspondent to an unknown recipient., 213; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - General Orders, 29 December 1812, issued by General James Wilkinson., 214; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 23 May 1814, E. B. Herman, Williamsburg, Virginia, to Rachel Mordecai of Warrenton, North Carolina., 215; 8 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 25 January 1815, Petersburg Volunteers to Anna Matilda Hening. Includes her reply., 216; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 15 May 1818, John McCarty to General Armistead T. Mason., 217; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 25 September 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer in London to John Randolph of Roanoke., 218; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 6 March 1826, Gilbert Stuart, Boston, [Massachusetts], to unknown recipient., 219; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 26 May 1839, Major J. D. Graham to Secretary of War Joel Poinsett regarding cadet Philip Kearney., 220; 1 leaf, typewritten with copy.
    - Letter, 16 September 1852, John Tyler, Jr., to Henry A. Wise., 221; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 7 November 1856, John Tyler, Jr., to Henry A. Wise., 222; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 16 April 1862, J. R. Bryan, [Gloucester County, Virginia], to D. C. Randolph., 223; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 21 July 1863,"A Soldier" to Corbelia Hancock. Also includes a letter from Hancock to her mother., 224; 3 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 16 December 1865,. R. E. Lee, Lexington, [Virginia], to D.S.C. Cabell in the Senate of Virginia., 225; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Article, 3 February 1879, from the New York Sun reprinting a letter, 27 April 1868, of Horace Greeley., 226; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Notices, 1796-1838, from various Petersburg newspapers containing information on funerals, balls, sermons, sales, and sales of property. Also includes brief biographical information on Donald Mackenzie, Jane Osborne, Jane Jones, Susan Bott, James Campbell, and Edward Stokes., 227; 6 p., typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Peter[?] Lyons of Williamsburg to a merchant firm in London., 228; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, n.d., Winfield Scott to Andrew Jackson, and includes Jackson's reply. Also includes some genealogical information on Scott., 229; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Baron von Steuben to General George Washington., 230; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - n.d., John Bayne, Jr., Edenton, North Carolina, to William Elliott of Williamsburg, [Virginia].., 231; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Notes, n.d.,., 232; 2 p., handwritten
    - Letter, n.d., to "Tabitha.", 233; 2 p., handwritten copy.